In the last video, we started
在上一节视频里 我们讨论了
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
to talk about the kernels idea
核函数这个想法
and how it can be used to
以及怎样利用它去
define new features for the support vector machine.
实现支持向量机的一些新特性
In this video, I'd like to throw
在这一节视频中 我将
in some of the missing details and,
补充一些缺失的细节
also, say a few words about
并简单的介绍一下
how to use these ideas in practice.
怎么在实际中使用应用这些想法
Such as, how they pertain
例如 怎么处理
to, for example, the bias variance trade-off in support vector machines.
支持向量机中的偏差方差折中
In the last video, I talked
在上一节课中
about the process of picking a few landmarks.
我谈到过选择标记点
You know, l1, l2, l3 and that
例如 l1 l2 l3
allowed us to define the
这些点使我们能够定义
similarity function also called
相似度函数
the kernel or in this
也称之为核函数
example if you have
在这个例子里
this similarity function this is a Gaussian kernel.
我们的相似度函数为高斯核函数
And that allowed us to build
这使我们能够
this form of a hypothesis function.
构造一个模型
But where do we get these landmarks from?
但是 我们从哪里得到这些标记点？
Where do we get l1, l2, l3 from?
我们从哪里得到l1 l2 l3？
And it seems, also, that for complex learning
而且 在一些复杂的学习问题中
problems, maybe we want a
也许我们需要
lot more landmarks than just three of them that we might choose by hand.
更多的标记点 而不是我们手选的这三个
So in practice this is
因此 在实际应用时
how the landmarks are chosen
怎么选取标记点
which is that given the
是机器学习中必须解决的问题
machine learning problem. We have some
这是我们的数据集
data set of some some positive
有一些正样本和一些负样本
and negative examples. So, this is the idea here
我们的想法是
which is that we're gonna take the
我们将选取样本点
examples and for every
我们拥有的
training example that we have,
每一个样本点
we are just going to call
我们只需要直接使用它们
it. We're just going
我们直接
to put landmarks as exactly
将训练样本
the same locations as the training examples.
作为标记点
So if I have one training
如果我有一个
example if that is x1,
训练样本x1
well then I'm going
那么
to choose this is my first landmark
我将在这个样本点
to be at xactly the same location
精确一致的位置上
as my first training example.
选作我的第一个标记点
And if I have a different training
如果我有另一个
example x2. Well we're
训练样本x2
going to set the second landmark
那么 我将把第二个标记点选在
to be the location of my second training example.
与第二个样本点一致的位置上
On the figure on the right, I
在右边的这幅图上
used red and blue dots
我用红点和蓝点
just as illustration, the color
来阐述
of this figure, the color of
这幅图以及这些点的颜色
the dots on the figure on the right is not significant.
可能并不显眼
But what I'm going to end up
但是利用
with using this method is I'm
这个方法
going to end up with m
最终能得到
landmarks of l1, l2
m个标记点 l1 l2
down to l(m) if I
直到lm
have m training examples with
即每一个标记点
one landmark per location of
的位置都与
my per location of each
每一个样本点
of my training examples. And this is
的位置精确对应
nice because it is saying that
这个过程很棒
my features are basically going
这说明特征函数基本上
to measure how close an
是在描述
example is to one
每一个样本距离
of the things I saw in my training set.
样本集中其他样本的距离
So, just to write this outline a
我们具体的列出
little more concretely, given m
这个过程的大纲
training examples, I'm going
给定m个训练样本
to choose the the location
我将选取与
of my landmarks to be exactly
m个训练样本精确一致
near the locations of my m training examples.
的位置作为我的标记点
When you are given example x,
当输入样本x
and in this example x can be
样本x可以
something in the training set,
属于训练集
it can be something in the cross validation
也可以属于交叉验证集
set, or it can be something in the test set.
也可以属于测试集
Given an example x we are
给定样本x
going to compute, you know,
我们可以计算
these features as so f1,
这些特征 即f1
f2, and so on.
f2 以此类推
Where l1 is actually equal
这里l1等于x1
to x1 and so on.
剩下标记点的以此类推
And these then give me a feature vector.
最终我们能到一个特征向量
So let me write f as the feature vector.
我将特征向量记为f
I'm going to take these f1, f2 and
我将f1 f2等等
so on, and just group
构造为
them into feature vector.
特征向量
Take those down to fm.
一直写到fm
And, you know, just by convention.
此外 按照惯例
If we want, we can add an
如果我们需要的话
extra feature f0, which is always equal to 1.
可以添加额外的特征f0 f0的值始终为1
So this plays a role similar to what we had previously.
它与我们之前讨论过的
For x0, which was our interceptor.
截距x0的作用相似
So, for example, if we
举个例子
have a training example x(i), y(i),
假设我们右训练样本(xi, yi)
the features we would compute for
这个样本对应的
this training example will be
特征向量可以
as follows: given x(i), we
这样计算 给定xi
will then map it to, you know, f1(i).
我们可以通过相似度函数
Which is the similarity. I'm going to
将其映射到f1(i)
abbreviate as SIM instead of writing out the whole
在这里 我将整个单词similarity
word
简记为
similarity, right?
SIM
And f2(i) equals the similarity
f2(i)等于x(i)与l2
between x(i) and l2,
之间的相似度
and so on,
以此类推
down to fm(i) equals
最后有fm(i)
the similarity between x(i) and l(m).
等于x(i)与lm之间的相似度
And somewhere in the middle.
在这一列中间的
Somewhere in this list, you know, at
某个位置
the i-th component, I will
即第i个元素
actually have one feature
有一个特征
component which is f subscript
为fi(i)
i(i), which is
going to be the similarity
这是xi和li之间的
between x and l(i).
相似度
Where l(i) is equal to
这里l(i)就等于
x(i), and so you know
x(i) 所以
fi(i) is just going to
fi(i)衡量的是
be the similarity between x and itself.
x(i)与其自身的相似度
And if you're using the Gaussian kernel this is
如果你使用高斯核函数的话
actually e to the minus 0
这一项等于
over 2 sigma squared and so, this will be equal to 1 and that's okay.
exp(-0/(2*sigma^2)) 等于1
So one of my features for this
所以 对于这个样本来说
training example is going to be equal to 1.
其中的某一个特征等于1
And then similar to what I have above.
接下来 类似于我们之前的过程
I can take all of these
我将这m个特征
m features and group them into a feature vector.
合并为一个特征向量
So instead of representing my example,
于是 相比之前用x(i)来描述样本
using, you know, x(i) which is this what
x(i)为n维或者n+1维空间
R(n) plus R(n) one dimensional vector.
的向量
Depending on whether you can
取决于你的具体项数
set terms, is either R(n)
可能为n维向量空间
or R(n) plus 1.
也可能为n+1维向量空间
We can now instead represent my
我们现在可以用
training example using this feature
这个特征向量f
vector f. I am
来描述我的特征向量
going to write this f superscript i.  Which
我将合并f(i)
is going to be taking all
将所有这些项
of these things and stacking them into a vector.
合并为一个向量
So, f1(i) down
即从f1(i)
to fm(i) and if you want and
到fm(i) 如果有需要的话
well, usually we'll also add this
我们通常也会加上
f0(i), where
f0(i)这一项
f0(i) is equal to 1.
f0(i)等于1
And so this vector
那么 这个向量
here gives me my
就是
new feature vector with which
我们用于描述训练样本的
to represent my training example.
特征向量
So given these kernels
当给定核函数
and similarity functions, here's how
和相似度函数后
we use a simple vector machine.
我们按照这个方法来使用支持向量机
If you already have a learning
如果你已经得到参数theta
set of parameters theta, then if you given a value of x and you want to make a prediction.
并且想对样本x做出预测
What we do is we compute the
我们先要计算
features f, which is now
特征向量f
an R(m) plus 1 dimensional feature vector.
f是m+1维特征向量
And we have m here because we have
这里之所以有m
m training examples and thus
是因为我们有m个训练样本
m landmarks and what
于是就有m个标记点
we do is we predict
我们在theta的转置乘以f
1 if theta transpose f
大于或等于0时
is greater than or equal to 0.
预测y=1
Right.
具体一点
So, if theta transpose f, of course,
theta的转置乘以f
that's just equal to theta 0, f0 plus theta 1,
等于theta_0*f_0加上theta_1*f_1
f1 plus dot dot
加上点点点
dot, plus theta m
直到theta_m*f_m
f(m). And so my
所以
parameter vector theta is also now
参数向量theta
going to be an m
在这里为
plus 1 dimensional vector.
m+1维向量
And we have m here because where
这里有m是因为
the number of landmarks is equal
标记点的个数等于
to the training set size.
训练点的个数
So m was the training set size and now, the
m就是训练集的大小
parameter vector theta is going to be m plus one dimensional.
所以 参数向量theta为m+1维
So that's how you make a prediction
以上就是当已知参数theta时
if you already have a setting for the parameter's theta.
怎么做出预测的过程
How do you get the parameter's theta?
但是怎么得到参数theta？
Well you do that using the
你在使用
SVM learning algorithm, and specifically
SVM学习算法时
what you do is you would solve this minimization problem.
具体来说就是要求解这个最小化问题
You've minimized the parameter's
你需要求出能使这个式子取最小值的参数theta
theta of C times this cost function which we had before.
式子为C乘以这个我们之前见过的代价函数
Only now, instead of looking
只是在这里
there instead of making
相比之前使用
predictions using theta transpose
theta的转置乘以x^(i) 即我们的原始特征
x(i) using our original
做出预测
features, x(i). Instead we've
我们将替换
taken the features x(i)
特征向量x^(i)
and replace them with a new features
并使用这个新的特征向量
so we are using theta transpose
我们使用theta的转置
f(i) to make a
乘以f^(i)来对第i个训练样本
prediction on the i'f training
做出预测
examples and we see that, you know,
我们可以看到
in both places here and
这两个地方(都要做出替换)
it's by solving this minimization problem
通过解决这个最小化问题
that you get the parameters for your Support Vector Machine.
我们就能得到支持向量机的参数
And one last detail is
最后一个细节是
because this optimization
对于这个优化问题
problem we really have
我们有
n equals m features.
n=m个特征
That is here.
就在这里
The number of features we have.
我们拥有的特征个数
Really, the effective number of
显然 有效的特征个数
features we have is dimension
应该等于f的维数
of f. So that n
所以
is actually going to be equal
n其实就等于m
to m. So, if you want to, you can
如果愿意的话
think of this as a sum,
你也可以认为这是一个求和
this really is a sum
这确实就是
from j equals 1 through
j从1到m的累和
m. And then one way to think
可以这么来看这个问题
about this, is you can
你可以想象（这一段话有问题，待改）
think of it as n being
n就等于m
equal to m, because if
因为如果f
f isn't a new feature, then
不是新的特征向量
we have m plus 1
那么我们有m+1个特征
features, with the plus 1 coming from the interceptor.
额外的1是因为截距的关系
And here, we still do sum
因此这里
from j equal 1 through n,
我们仍要j从1累加到n
because similar to our
与我们之前
earlier videos on regularization,
视频中讲过的正则化类似
we still do not regularize the
我们仍然不对tehta_0
parameter theta zero, which is
做正则化处理
why this is a sum for
这就是
j equals 1 through m
j从1累加到m
instead of j equals zero though
而不是从0累加到m的原因
m.  So that's
以上
the support vector machine learning algorithm.
就是支持向量机的学习算法
That's one sort of, mathematical
我在这里
detail aside that I
还要讲到
should mention, which is
一个数学细节
that in the way the support
在支持向量机
vector machine is implemented, this last
实现的过程中
term is actually done a little bit differently.
这最后一项与这里写的有细微差别
So you don't really need to
其实在实现支持向量机时
know about this last detail in
你并不需要知道
order to use support vector machines,
这个细节
and in fact the equations that
事实上这写下的这个式子
are written down here should give
已经给你提供了
you all the intuitions that should need.
全部需要的原理
But in the way the support vector machine
但是在支持向量机实现的过程中
is implemented, you know, that term, the
这一项
sum of j of theta j squared right?
theta_j从1到m的平方和
Another way to write this is this can
这一项可以被重写为
be written as theta transpose
theta的转置
theta if we ignore
乘以theta
the parameter theta 0.
如果我们忽略theta_0的话
So theta 1 down to
考虑theta_1直到theta_m
theta m.  Ignoring theta 0.
并忽略theta_0
Then this sum of
那么
j of theta j squared that this
theta_j的平方和
can also be written theta transpose theta.
可以被重写为theta的转置乘以theta
And what most support vector
大多数支持向量机
machine implementations do is actually
在实现的时候
replace this theta transpose theta,
其实是替换掉theta的转置乘以theta
will instead, theta transpose times
用theta的转置乘以
some matrix inside, that depends
某个矩阵 这依赖于你采用的核函数
on the kernel you use, times theta.
再乘以theta的转置
And so this gives us a slightly different distance metric.
这其实是另一种略有区别的距离度量方法
We'll use a slightly different
我们用一种略有变化的
measure instead of minimizing exactly
度量来取代
the norm of theta squared means
theta的模的平方
that minimize something slightly similar to it.
这意味着我们最小化了一种类似的度量
That's like a rescale version of
这是参数向量theta的变尺度版本
the parameter vector theta that depends on the kernel.
这种变化和核函数相关
But this is kind of a mathematical detail.
这个数学细节
That allows the support vector
使得支持向量机
machine software to run much more efficiently.
能够更有效率的运行
And the reason the support vector machine
支持向量机做这种修改的
does this is with this modification.
理由是
It allows it to
这么做可以适应
scale to much bigger training sets.
超大的训练集
Because for example, if you have
例如
a training set with 10,000 training examples.
当你的训练集有10000个样本时
Then, you know, the way we define
根据我们之前定义标记点的方法
landmarks, we end up with 10,000 landmarks.
我们最终有10000个标记点
And so theta becomes 10,000 dimensional.
theta也随之是10000维的向量
And maybe that works, but when m
或许这时这么做还可行
becomes really, really big
但是 当m变得非常非常大时
then solving for all
那么求解
of these parameters, you know, if m were
这么多参数
50,000 or a 100,000
如果m为50,000或者100,000
then solving for
此时
all of these parameters can become
利用支持向量机软件包
expensive for the support
来解决我写在这里的最小化问题
vector machine optimization software, thus
求解这些参数的成本
solving the minimization problem that I drew here.
会非常高
So kind of as mathematical
这些都是数学细节
detail, which again you really don't need to know about.
事实上你没有必要了解这些
It actually modifies that last
它实际上
term a little bit to
细微的修改了最后一项
optimize something slightly different than
使得最终的优化目标
just minimizing the norm squared of theta squared, of theta.
与直接最小化theta的模的平方略有区别
But if you want,
如果愿意的话
you can feel free to think
你可以直接认为
of this as an kind of a n implementational detail
这个具体的实现细节
that does change the objective a
尽管略微的改变了
bit, but is done primarily
优化目标
for reasons of computational efficiency,
但是它主要是为了计算效率
so usually you don't really have to worry about this.
所以 你不必要对此有太多担心
And by the way, in case your
顺便说一下
wondering why we don't apply
你可能会想为什么我们不将
the kernel's idea to other
核函数这个想法
algorithms as well like logistic
应用到其他算法 比如逻辑回归上
regression, it turns out
事实证明
that if you want, you
如果愿意的话
can actually apply the kernel's
确实可以将核函数
idea and define the source
这个想法用于定义特征向量
of features using landmarks and so on for logistic regression.
将标记点之类的技术用于逻辑回归算法
But the computational tricks that apply
但是用于支持向量机
for support vector machines don't
的计算技巧
generalize well to other algorithms like logistic regression.
不能较好的推广到其他算法诸如逻辑回归上
And so, using kernels with
所以 将核函数用于
logistic regression is going too
逻辑回归时
very slow, whereas, because of
会变得非常的慢
computational tricks, like that
相比之下 这些计算技巧
embodied and how it modifies
比如具体化技术
this and the details of how
对这些细节的修改
the support vector machine software is
以及支持向量软件的实现细节
implemented, support vector machines and
使得支持向量机
kernels tend go particularly well together.
可以和核函数相得益彰
Whereas, logistic regression and kernels,
而逻辑回归和核函数
you know, you can do it, but this would run very slowly.
则运行得十分缓慢
And it won't be able to
更何况它们还不能
take advantage of advanced optimization
使用那些高级优化技巧
techniques that people have figured
因为这些技巧
out for the particular case
是人们专门为
of running a support vector machine with a kernel.
使用核函数的支持向量机开发的
But all this pertains only
但是这些问题只有
to how you actually implement
在你亲自实现最小化函数
software to minimize the cost function.
才会遇到
I will say more about that in
我将在下一节视频中
the next video, but you really don't
进一步讨论这些问题
need to know about
但是 你并不需要知道
how to write software to
怎么去写一个软件
minimize this  cost function because
来最小化代价函数
you can find very good off the shelf software for doing so.
你能找到很好的成熟软件来做些
And just as, you know, I wouldn't
与我
recommend writing code to invert
不建议自己写矩阵求逆函数
a matrix or to compute a
或者平方根函数
square root, I actually do
的道理一样
not recommend writing software to
我也不建议亲自写
minimize this cost function yourself,
最小化代价函数的代码
but instead to use off
而应该使用
the shelf software packages that people
人们开发的
have developed and so
成熟的软件包
those software packages already embody
这些软件包
these numerical optimization tricks,
已经包含了那些数值优化技巧
so you don't really have to worry about them.
所以你不必担心这些东西
But one other thing that is
但是另外一个
worth knowing about is when
值得说明的问题是
you're applying a support vector
在你使用支持向量机时
machine, how do you
怎么选择
choose the parameters of the support vector machine?
支持向量机中的参数？
And the last thing I want to
在本节视频的末尾
do in this video is say a
我想稍微说明一下
little word about the bias and
在使用支持向量机时的
variance trade offs when using a support vector machine.
偏差-方差折中
When using an SVM, one of
在使用支持向量机时
the things you need to choose is
其中一个要选择的事情是
the parameter C which
目标函数中的
was in the optimization objective, and
参数C
you recall that C played a
回忆一下
role similar to 1 over
C的作用与1/lambda相似
lambda, where lambda was the regularization
lambda时逻辑回归算法中
parameter we had for logistic regression.
的正则化参数
So, if you have a
所以
large value of C, this corresponds
大的C对应着
to what we have back in logistic
我们以前在逻辑回归
regression, of a small
问题中的小的lambda
value of lambda meaning of not using much regularization.
这意味着不使用正则化
And if you do that, you
如果你这么做
tend to have a hypothesis with lower bias and higher variance.
就有可能得到一个低偏差但高方差的模型
Whereas if you use a smaller
如果你使用了
value of C then this
较小的C
corresponds to when we
这对应着
are using logistic regression with a
在逻辑回归问题中
large value of lambda and that corresponds
使用较大的lambda
to a hypothesis with higher
对应着一个高偏差
bias and lower variance.
但是低方差的模型
And so, hypothesis with large
所以
C has a higher
使用较大C值的模型
variance, and is more prone
为高方差
to overfitting, whereas hypothesis with
更倾向于过拟合
small C has higher bias
而使用较小C值的模型为高偏差
and is thus more prone to underfitting.
更倾向于欠拟合
So this parameter C is one of the parameters we need to choose.
C只是我们要选择的其中一个参数
The other one is the parameter
另外一个要选择的参数是
sigma squared, which appeared in the Gaussian kernel.
高斯核函数中的sigma^2
So if the Gaussian kernel
当高斯核函数中的
sigma squared is large, then
sigma^2偏大时
in the similarity function, which
那么对应的相似度函数
was this you know E to the
为exp(-||x-l^(i)||^2/(2*sigma^2))
minus x minus landmark
exp(-||x-l^(i)||^2/(2*sigma^2))
varies squared over 2 sigma squared.
In this one of the example; If I
在这个例子中
have only one feature, x1, if
如果我们只有一个特征x_1
I have a landmark there at
我们在这个位置
that location, if sigma
有一个标记点
squared is large, then, you know, the
如果sigma^2较大
Gaussian kernel would tend to
那么高斯核函数
fall off relatively slowly
倾向于变得相对平滑
and so this would be my feature
这可能是我的特征f_i
f(i), and so this
所以
would be smoother function that varies
由于函数平滑
more smoothly, and so this will
且变化的比较平缓
give you a hypothesis with higher
这会给你的模型
bias and lower variance, because
带来较高的偏差和较低的方差
the Gaussian kernel that falls off smoothly,
由于高斯核函数变得平缓
you tend to get a hypothesis that
就更倾向于得到一个
varies slowly, or varies smoothly
随着输入x
as you change the
变化得缓慢的模型
input x. Whereas in contrast,
反之
if sigma squared was
如果sigma^2很小
small and if that's my
这是我的标记点
landmark given my 1
利用其给出特征x_1
feature x1, you know, my Gaussian
那么
kernel, my similarity function, will vary more abruptly.
高斯核函数 即相似度函数会变化的很剧烈
And in both cases I'd pick
我们标记出这两种情况下1的位置
out 1, and so if sigma squared
在sigma^2较小的情况下
is small, then my features vary less smoothly.
特征的变化会变得不平滑
So if it's just higher slopes
会有较大的斜率
or higher derivatives here.
和较大的导数
And using this, you end
在这种情况下
up fitting hypotheses of lower
最终得到的模型会
bias and you can have higher variance.
是低偏差和高方差
And if you look at this
如果你看了
week's points exercise, you actually get
本周的编程作业
to play around with some
你就能亲自实现这些想法
of these ideas yourself and see these effects yourself.
并亲眼看到这些效果
So, that was the support vector machine with kernels algorithm.
这就是利用核函数的支持向量机算法
And hopefully this discussion of
希望这些关于
bias and variance will give
偏差和方差的讨论
you some sense of how you
能给你一些
can expect this algorithm to behave as well.
对于算法结果预期的直观印象